<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<TranscendenceModule>
	
	<!-- Hunt for Antarctica ===================================================

	EXTRA DATA
		targetID:		ID of the CSC Antarctica

	======================================================================== -->
	
	<MissionType UNID="&msHuntForAntarctica;"
			name=				"Hunt for CSC Antarctica"
			attributes=			"commonwealthFleet, cscTerra, rank5, rank6"

			level=				"9"

			maxAppearing=		"1"
			noDecline=			"true"
			>

		<Events>
			<OnCreate>
				(switch
					;	No mission if we've already meet Antarctica
					(rpgCharacterGetQuickRel &unidCaptainHelios;)
						(msnDestroy gSource)

					;	Or if the Antarctica is destroyed
					(rpgCharacterGetStatus &unidCaptainHelios;)
						(msnDestroy gSource)

					;	Set up the mission
					(block (
						(targetObj (sysFindObject Nil "sN +cscAntarctica;"))
						)
						(if targetObj
							(block Nil
								(msnSetData gSource 'targetID (objGetID targetObj))
								(msnRegisterForEvents gSource targetObj)
								)
							)
						)
					)
			</OnCreate>

			<OnObjDestroyed>
				(switch
					;	Antarctica destroyed

					(= (objGetID aObjDestroyed) (msnGetData gSource 'targetID))
						(switch
							;	If the Antarctica entered a stargate, then this mission
							;	failed.

							(= aDestroyReason 'enteredStargate)
								(msnFailure gSource)

							;	If the Antarctica ascended, then it just means the player 
							;	left the system. We figure out whether or not it was
							;	able to escape.

							(= aDestroyReason 'ascended)
								(block (
									(missionObj (@ (msnFind "ao +unid:&msEscapeFromDantalion;;") 0))
									)
									(switch

										;	If the mission is not accepted, then we skip. If the
										;	player goes back, they can continue the mission.

										(not missionObj)
											Nil

										;	If the mission was declined, and the Antarctica 
										;	ascended, then it means that she escaped.

										(msnGetProperty missionObj 'isDeclined)
											(msnFailure gSource)

										;	If there are cruisers left, then we assume that the
										;	Antarctica was destroyed.

										(gr (msnGetData missionObj 'cruisersLeft) 0)
											(msnSuccess gSource)

										;	Otherwise, we assume the Antarctica survived.

										(msnFailure gSource)
										)
									)

							;	Otherwise, the Antarctica was destroyed.

							(msnSuccess gSource)
							)
					)
			</OnObjDestroyed>

			<OnDebriefed>
				(block (
					(status (rpgCharacterGetStatus &unidCaptainHelios;))
					(stationObj (objGetObjByID (msnGetProperty gSource 'ownerID)))
					missionObj
					)
					(switch
						(msnGetProperty gSource 'isFailure)
							(block Nil
								(objSetData gPlayerShip 'fleetXP 600)
								(objSetData gPlayerShip 'fleetLevel 3)
								(typSetData &msCSCLamplighterTesting; 'status 'notPlayer)
								)
						(= status 'betrayed)
							(typSetData &msCSCLamplighterTesting; 'status 'notPlayer)

						(= status 'destroyedByPlayer)
							(block Nil
								(typSetData &msCSCLamplighterTesting; 'status 'player)

								;	Create the mission now so player can go straight to dockmaster
								(if (setq missionObj (msnCreate &msCSCLamplighterTesting; stationObj))
									(msnAccept missionObj)
									)
								)

						(= status 'destroyed)
							(typSetData &msCSCLamplighterTesting; 'status 'fleetCaptain)
						)
					)
			</OnDebriefed>

			<OnGlobalSystemStarted>
				(enum (msnFind "a +unid:&msHuntForAntarctica;;") theMission
					(if (not (msnGetData gSource 'targetID))
						(block (
							(targetObj (sysFindObject Nil "sN +cscAntarctica;"))
							)
							(if targetObj
								(block Nil
									(msnSetData theMission 'targetID (objGetID targetObj))
									(msnRegisterForEvents theMission targetObj)
									)
								)
							)
						)
					)
			</OnGlobalSystemStarted>
		</Events>
		
		<Language>
			<!-- Code Points -->

			<Text id="Summary">
				(cat
					(msnTranslate gSource 'textSummary)
					"\n\n"
					(typTranslate &dsRPGMission; 'mission.rewardSummary {
						systemName: (sysGetName)
						payment: (fmtCurrency 'credit (msnGetData gSource 'reward))
						})
					)
			</Text>
			<Text id="Intro">
				(list
					{	textID: 'textIntro1	}
					{	textID: 'textIntro2	}
					{	textID: (if (= (objGetProperty gPlayerShip 'characterClass) &unidPilgrimClass;)
							'textIntro3Pilgrim
							'textIntro3
							)
						data: { shipName:(objGetName gPlayerShip 0x05) }
						}
					)
			</Text>
			<Text id="Briefing">
				(list
					{	textID: 'textBriefing1	}
					{	textID: 'textBriefing2	}
					{	textID: 'textBriefing3	}
					)
			</Text>
			<Text id="InProgress">
				(block (
					(missionTime (- (unvGetTick) (msnGetProperty gSource 'acceptedOn)))
					)
					(list
						{
							textID: (switch
								(sysFindObject Nil "sA +cscAntarctica;")
									'textProgressInSystem

								(ls missionTime 300)
									'textProgress1

								(ls missionTime 1800)
									'textProgress2

								'textProgress3
								)
							}
						)
					)
			</Text>
			<Text id="FailureDebrief">
				(list
					{ textID: 'textFailure1 }
					{ textID: 'textFailure2 }
					)
			</Text>
			<Text id="SuccessDebrief">
				(block (
					(status (rpgCharacterGetStatus &unidCaptainHelios;))
					)
					(switch
						(= status 'betrayed)
							(list
								{ textID: 'textBetrayed1 }
								{ textID: 'textBetrayed2 }
								)

						(= status 'destroyedByPlayer)
							(list
								{ textID: 'textSuccessPlayer1 }
								{ textID: 'textSuccessPlayer2 }
								)

						(= status 'destroyed)
							(list
								{ textID: 'textSuccess1 }
								{ textID: (if (geq (objGetData gPlayerShip 'fleetLevel) 6)
									'textSuccessCaptain2
									'textSuccess2
									)}
								)

						(cat "ERROR: Antarctica status: " (or status "Nil"))
						)
					)
			</Text>

			<!-- Text -->

			<Text id="Name">
				Hunt for the CSC Antarctica
			</Text>
			<Text id="textSummary">
				The CSC Antarctica has gone rogue. Admiral Decker has ordered
				you to locate and destroy the carrier.
			</Text>
			<Text id="textIntro1">
				As you enter the bridge, you see Admiral Conrad Decker talking
				with his XO. A guard approaches you and says,

				"The admiral would like you to wait for him at his quarters."
			</Text>
			<Text id="textIntro2">
				Waiting in the admiral's quarters you see the artifacts of his
				life scattered around the room&mdash;charts, papers, and empty
				glasses are randomly distributed. Pictures of the men and women
				that he's lost judge from the walls.

				Fifteen minutes later, the admiral walks in.
			</Text>
			<Text id="textIntro3">
				"%shipName% armed like a battleship out here at the edge. What
				are you looking for?"

				"I'll make a deal with you. Help me with my problem and I'll
				give you something that will help you."
			</Text>
			<Text id="textIntro3Pilgrim">
				"%shipName% armed like a battleship and a lonely pilot heading
				for the Core. Another plaything for the Gods. What a waste.

				"I'll make a deal with you. Help me with my problem and I'll
				give you something you're going to need out there."
			</Text>
			<Text id="textBriefing1">
				"My problem is Captain Helios and the CSC Antarctica. Two months
				ago we were on joint operations against an Ares stronghold. Four
				carriers; hundreds of Centurions; one of the most complicated
				operations of the war."

				"A light-minute out, she breaks formation and recalls her wing.
				She left us out there at the most critical point!"
			</Text>
			<Text id="textBriefing2">
				"She's gone rogue. Or worse. And with a carrier. And with the
				secrets she knows... I really don't have a choice."

				The admiral looks away, out the porthole. He looks tired. And
				old.
			</Text>
			<Text id="textBriefing3">
				When the admiral turns back to you there is a new intensity in
				his eyes and as he stands up his fists are clenched.

				"Your mission is to hunt down the Antarctica. And to destroy
				her, if you can."
			</Text>
			<Text id="textProgressInSystem">
				Admiral Decker talks with his XO at his center console. They see
				you enter, and the admiral comes up to you quietly:

				"We've had a sighting of the Antarctica somewhere in this system!
				You know what to do. Return here when you've accomplished your
				mission."
			</Text>
			<Text id="textProgress1">
				The bridge of the CSC Terra is chaotic, but efficient. Various
				officers discuss issues at their panels, raising their voice
				above the chatter of comm traffic. The admiral is not on the
				bridge, but the XO approaches you:

				"I don't envy your mission. We don't have fresh intel on the
				Antarctica; you'll have to search system by system, I'm afraid."
			</Text>
			<Text id="textProgress2">
				Admiral Decker talks with his XO at the center of a chaotic, but
				efficient bridge. The Admiral sees you come in, but he seems too
				busy to be able to talk to you.
			</Text>
			<Text id="textProgress3">
				Admiral Decker talks with his XO at his center console. They see
				you enter, and the XO comes up to you quietly:

				"Still no sign of the Antarctica. We've had reports that it
				might be in the Dantalion system."
			</Text>
			<Text id="textFailure1">
				The bridge grows quiet as you enter. All the officers stare at
				you, some with disgust, others with pity. The XO walks up to you:
				"The admiral is waiting for you in his quarters."
			</Text>
			<Text id="textFailure2">
				The admiral broods in his chambers. He stares at you coldly:
				
				"What happened out there? How did the Antarctica escape? If I
				ever find out that you helped them, I will make sure that you
				hang as a traitor! Until then, you are demoted to Master
				Sergeant. Now get the hell out of here."
			</Text>
			<Text id="textSuccessPlayer1">
				As you enter the bridge all the officers rise and applaud.
				Admiral Decker stands next to you and says,

				"The Fleet owes you a great debt. The valor and heroism that you
				showed in defeating the Antarctica will stand as a beacon of
				hope in this bloody war!"

				After much cheering and congratulations, the Admiral leads you
				to his quarters for a private conversation.
			</Text>
			<Text id="textSuccessPlayer2">
				"You've done your part of the bargain, now let me help you with
				your journey. For the last few years we've been working on a new
				weapon&mdash;something that can hurt the Ares and win this war. I
				want you to test this new weapon. The dockmaster will install it.
				Good luck!"
			</Text>
			<Text id="textSuccess1">
				As you enter the bridge all the officers cheer. Admiral Decker
				stands next to you and announces,

				"I can now confirm that the rogue ship Antarctica has been destroyed!"

				After much cheering, the Admiral leads you to his quarters for a
				private conversation.
			</Text>
			<Text id="textSuccessCaptain2">
				"Thanks for tracking down the Antarctica&mdash;we couldn't have
				done it without you. Now it's my turn to help you."
				
				"For the last few years we've been working on a new
				weapon&mdash;something that will win this war. I want you to test
				it. Report to the dockmaster and he will explain. Good luck!"
			</Text>
			<Text id="textSuccess2">
				"Thanks for tracking down the Antarctica&mdash;we couldn't have
				done it without you. I know you're on your way to the Core,	but
				if you stay with the Fleet and make captain, I guarantee that
				I'll remember your service. Good luck, and remember what I said."
			</Text>
			<Text id="textBetrayed1">
				The bridge grows quiet as you enter. All the officers stare at
				you, some with disgust, others with pity. The XO walks up to you:
				"The admiral is waiting for you in his quarters."
			</Text>
			<Text id="textBetrayed2">
				The admiral sits at his desk quietly studying you. He says,
				
				"You're a cold-blooded killer, do you know that? I heard how you
				betrayed Captain Helios. I know she deserved it, but I'm glad
				that you're leaving Human Space. I'll see you in hell."
			</Text>
		</Language>
	</MissionType>

</TranscendenceModule>
