<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<TranscendenceModule>
	
	<!-- Fiona in St. Katharine's Star =========================================

	EXTRA DATA
	
	======================================================================== -->
	
	<MissionType UNID="&msFionaInStKats;"
			name=				"Fiona in St. Kats"
			attributes=			"benedictStoryArc, stKatsHospital"

			level=				"4"
			maxAppearing=		"1"
			priority=			"100"

			noDebrief=			"true"
			>

		<StaticData>
			<sequence>50</sequence>
		</StaticData>

		<Events>
			<OnCreate>
				(block ()
					(switch
						;	See if the mission is still available

						(not (benedict_isMissionAvailable (objGetType gSource)))
							(msnDestroy gSource)
							
						;	OK
						)
					)
			</OnCreate>

			<OnAccepted>
				(block (
					)
					;	Mission accepted
					
					(benedict_missionAccepted gSource)
					)
			</OnAccepted>

			<OnSetPlayerTarget>
			</OnSetPlayerTarget>
			
			<OnObjDestroyed>
			</OnObjDestroyed>
		</Events>
		
		<Language>
			<Text id="Name">"Contact Hugo Sandoval"</Text>
			<Text id="Summary">
				(cat
					"Go to " (sysGetName 'C5) " and find Hugo Sandoval. He flies a heavily modified Armstrong-class transport.\n\n"
					"System: " (sysGetName 'C5) "\n"
					"Payment: None"
					)
			</Text>
			<Text id="Intro">
				(list
					{
						desc: (cat
							"You enter the brightly lit central garden of the New Victoria University Hospital. "
							"Recovering patients sit on articulated gurneys, while doctors and medtechs pass through, "
							"heads buried in datapads.\n\n"
							
							"Nearby, Fiona rests at a bench, hooked up to a medical bot:\n\n"
							
							"\"I'm glad to finally meet you. Thank you for saving my life in Eridani.\""
							)
							
						label: "\"[D]o you remember what happened?\""
						}
					{
						desc: (cat
							"Fiona looks around and engages a privacy screen.\n\n"
							
							"\"Look, I don't know you, OK? Thanks again, but everything is fine.\""
							)
							
						label: "\"[B]enedict is worried about you.\""
						}
					{
						desc: (cat
							"Fiona blinks tears away and looks down.\n\n"
							
							"\"I don't know who to trust, OK?\"\n\n"
							
							"She pauses for a long time and then sits up straight to face you. A fresh scar "
							"curves under her left eye and disappears behind her ear."
							)
						}
					{
						desc: (cat
							"\"I was investigating a murder. A medtech on our mobile clinic found dead. "
							"I talked to Sister Elana Ston, in charge of the clinic. She said the medical "
							"ship had been ambushed by marauders and that the medtech may have tipped them off. "
							"Thought the marauders had spaced her too.\""
							)
							
						label: "\"A [S]ister in league with marauders?\""
						}
					{
						desc: (cat
							"\"Yeah, I know it doesn't make sense, OK? But I couldn't find any other evidence, "
							"and the medical ship had recently been lost in combat, so it fit.\n\n"
							
							"\"But then I got a strange message.\""
							)
							
						label: "\"[L]et me guess, Stormhound, right?\""
						}
					{
						desc: (cat
							"Fiona arches an eyebrow, impressed.\n\n"
							
							"\"Yes! He said it wasn't marauders. He told me to look for the wreckage of the medical ship in the "
							(sysGetName 'C5) " system. Asked to tell him what I found.\n\n"
							
							"\"But I never got there. Penitents attacked me on my way and here I am.\""
							)
							
						label: "\"[W]ho knows about this? Benedict?\""
						}
					{
						desc: (cat
							"Fiona stares at you.\n\n"
							
							"\"No. Not yet. Stormhound told me about his past. I'm questioning everything, OK?\""
							)
						
						actions: (list
							{
								label: "\"[Y]ou can trust Benedict.\""
								nextPage: 'trustBenedict
								}
							{
								label: "\"[D]on't trust Benedict.\""
								nextPage: 'dontTrustBenedict
								}
							)
						}
					{
						id: 'trustBenedict
						desc: (cat
							"Fiona closes her eyes and smiles.\n\n"
							
							"\"I want to believe that, OK? I really do. But I can't take the chance that I'm wrong.\""
							)
							
						label: "\"[W]hat do we do now?\""
						nextPage: 'exitPane
						}
					{
						id: 'dontTrustBenedict
						desc: (cat
							"Fiona closes her eyes and frowns.\n\n"
							
							"\"I don't know anymore. But either way, I can't take the chance that he's turned.\""
							)
						
						label: "\"[W]hat do we do now?\""
						nextPage: 'exitPane
						}
					)
			</Text>
			<Text id="Briefing">
				(list
					{
						desc: (cat
							"Fiona brings up a starmap on her datapad.\n\n"
							
							"\"I'm going to need your help. Go to the " (sysGetName 'C5) " system and "
							"get in touch with Hugo Sandoval. He's a friend of mine. He's a merc, but "
							"I can trust him.\n\n"
							
							"\"Together you should be able to find the wreckage of Sister Ston's medical "
							"ship. Perhaps we'll scrape off a clue.\""
							)
							
						acceptLabel: "\"[I]'m on my way.\""
						declineLabel: "\"[L]et me prepare first.\""
						}
					)
			</Text>
			<Text id="AcceptReply">
				(cat
					"\"Good luck, %name%!\""
					)
			</Text>
			<Text id="DeclineReply">
				(cat
					"\"Alright, but don't take long. Something tells me we don't have much time.\""
					)
			</Text>
			<Text id="InProgress">
				(cat
					"\"Something tells me we don't have much time. The sooner you reach Sandoval, the better!\""
					)
			</Text>
			<Text id="SuccessMsg">
				""
			</Text>
		</Language>
	</MissionType>
	
</TranscendenceModule>
