<?xml version="1.0" ?>

<TranscendenceModule>

	<!-- Mission: Huygens Explorer =============================================


	EXTRA DATA

	destID:				ID of the Huygens Explorer
	targetID:			ID of current mission target
	targetIDs:			List of all target IDs (buoys and Huygens)

	status:
		Nil:				Mission not yet started
		'searching			Player is still searching for the Huygens
		'foundHuygens		Player has docked with the Huygens
		'foundRom			Player has returned to Ringers with the research ROM

	======================================================================== -->

	<MissionType UNID="&msHereticHuygensExplorer;"
			name=			"Huygens Explorer"
			attributes=		"ringersResearch, hereticMission, deliveryMission"

			level=			"10"

			maxAppearing=	"1"
			>

		<Events>
			<OnCreate>
				(switch
					;	This mission only works in Heretic
					(!= (sysGetNode) 'G2)
						(msnDestroy gSource)

					;	Set up the mission
					(block Nil
						)
					)
			</OnCreate>

			<OnStarted>
				(block (
					(baseObj (objGetObjByID (msnGetProperty gSource 'ownerID)))
					curObj prevObj thePos theRom targetIDs
					)
					;	Create the Heretic research ROM
					(setq theRom (itmSetData (itmCreate &itHereticResearchROM; 1) 'missionID (objGetID gSource)))
					(msnSetData gSource 'researchROM theRom)

					(for i 1 6
						(block Nil
							(if (not thePos)
								;	First buoy should be close to station and system center
								(loop (or (not thePos) (gr (sysVectorDistance buoyPos) 400))
									(setq thePos (sysVectorRandom baseObj 200 90 "TA"))
									)
								;	Remaining buoys spiral outwards
								(block (
									(angle (modulo (+ (sysVectorAngle thePos) (random 30 90)) 360))
									(radius (min (+ -60 (* i 150) (random 15 60)) 900))
									)
									(setq thePos (sysVectorRandom
										(sysVectorPolarOffset Nil angle radius)
										(lambda Nil (random 5 60))
										50
										"TA"
										))
									)
								)

							(if (= i 6)
								;	Final location is the Huygens
								(block Nil
									(setq curObj (sysCreateShip &scHuygensExplorer; thePos &svSentinelAI;))
									(objSetEventHandler curObj &evHereticHuygensExplorer;)
									(objFireEvent curObj 'OnBehaviorStart)

									(objAddItem curObj theRom)
									(msnRegisterForEvents gSource curObj)
									(msnSetData gSource 'destID (objGetID curObj))
									)

								;	Otherwise create a buoy
								(block (
									(theDay (+ 3 (* i 2) (random 0 1)))
									(theHour (random 0 23))
									(theMinute (random 0 59))
									(theSecond (random 0 59))
									(logTime (cat "2419-01-"
										(if (ls theDay 10) "0" "") theDay " "
										(if (ls theHour 10) "0" "") theHour ":"
										(if (ls theMinute 10) "0" "") theMinute ":"
										(if (ls theSecond 10) "0" "") theSecond
										))
									(logText (cat
										(msnTranslate gSource 'textLog)
										"\n" logTime "\n\n"
										(msnTranslate gSource (cat "textLog" i))
										))
									)
									(setq curObj (sysCreateStation &stLogBuoy; thePos))
									(objSetData curObj 'logText logText)
									)
								)

							;	Create some additional objects at each point
							(switch
								; If we're at the first buoy, create some wrecks around the area
								(= i 1)
									(block Nil
										(sysCreateShipwreck &scIocrymSentinel; (sysVectorPolarOffset thePos (random 0 359) 4) &svNeutral;)
										(for j 1 (random 3 4)
											(sysCreateShipwreck &scLuminousDrone; (sysVectorPolarOffset thePos (random 0 359) (random 5 12)) &svNeutral;)
											)
										)

								;	At the 5th buoy, create a centurion wreck
								(= i 5)
									(block (theWreck theMessage)
										(setq theWreck (sysCreateShipwreck &scCenturionM; (sysVectorPolarOffset thePos (random 0 359) (random 4 12)) &svNeutral;))
										(setq theMessage (itmCreate &itDataROM; 1))
										(setq theMessage (itmSetData theMessage 'Text (msnTranslate gSource 'textWarning)))
										(objAddItem theWreck theMessage)
										)
								)

							(lnkAppend targetIDs (objGetID curObj))

							;	The previous buoy should point to this one
							;(if prevObj (objSetObjRefData prevObj 'nextObj curObj))
							;(setq prevObj curObj)
							)
						)
					;	Save the list of all target IDs
					(msnSetData gSource 'targetIDs targetIDs)
					(msnSetData gSource 'targetID (@ targetIDs 0))
					)
			</OnStarted>

			<OnAcceptedUndock>
				(block Nil
					(msnSetData gSource 'status 'searching)
					(msnRegisterForEvents gSource gPlayerShip)
					)
			</OnAcceptedUndock>

			<OnObjDocked>
				(block (
					(targetIDs (msnGetData gSource 'targetIDs))
					targetNum
					)
					(switch
						(!= aObjDocked gPlayerShip)
							Nil

						(= (objGetID aDockTarget) (msnGetProperty gSource 'ownerID))
							(if (objHasItem gPlayerShip (msnGetData gSource 'researchROM))
								(msnSetData gSource 'status 'foundROM)
								)

						;	Huygens is handled by delivery mission code
						(= (objGetID aDockTarget) (msnGetData gSource 'destID))
							Nil

						;	If we've docked with a buoy then point player to the next one
						(setq targetNum (find targetIDs (objGetID aDockTarget)))
							(block Nil
								(msnSetData gSource 'targetID (@ targetIDs (+ targetNum 1)))
								(msnSetPlayerTarget gSource)
								)
								
						)
					)
			</OnObjDocked>

			<OnDeliveryMissionCompleted>
				(block (
					(huygensObj (objGetObjByID (msnGetData gSource 'destID)))
					)
					(sovSetDisposition &svSentinelAI; &svPlayer; 'enemy)
					(sovSetDisposition &svPlayer; &svSentinelAI; 'enemy)

					(shpCancelOrders huygensObj)
					(shpOrder huygensObj 'wait 5)
					(shpOrder huygensObj 'attack gPlayerShip)

					(msnSetData gSource 'status 'foundHuygens)

					{desc: (msnTranslate gSource 'textDockHuygens) forceUndock:True}
					)
			</OnDeliveryMissionCompleted>

			<OnSetPlayerTarget>
				(rpgSetTarget gSource aReason (objGetObjByID (msnGetData gSource 'targetID)))
			</OnSetPlayerTarget>

			<OnObjDestroyed>
				(switch
					;	If Huygens is destroyed then mission succeeds
					(= (objGetID aObjDestroyed) (msnGetData gSource 'destID))
						(msnSuccess gSource)
					)
			</OnObjDestroyed>

			<OnCanBrief>
				(if (msnFind "a +hereticMission;")
					(msnTranslate gSource 'textBusy)
					)
			</OnCanBrief>
		</Events>

		<Language>
			<!-- Code Points -->

			<Text id="Name">
				Search for the Huygens Explorer
			</Text>
			<Text id="Summary">
				(msnTranslate gSource 'textSummary {
					systemName: (sysGetName)
					})
			</Text>

			<Text id="SuccessDebrief">
				(list
					(if (= (msnGetData gSource 'status) 'foundROM)
						{	textID: 'textSuccessFoundROM	}
						{	textID: 'textSuccessSeekROM		}
						)
					)
			</Text>

			<!-- Text -->

			<Text id="textSummary">

				The Ringers have lost communications with the Huygens Explorer.
				Your mission is to investigate and provide any assistance they
				may require.

				System: %systemName%\n
				Payment: None

			</Text>
			<Text id="Intro">

				A young ringer greets you as you enter the lab. His melodic
				voice is translated through a device on his neck:

				"Earthican, welcome! We seek answers to questions related to Iocrym.
				We seek answers to questions related to their intentions. All
				human-descendents are interested. Ringer and Earthican are united."

			</Text>
			<Text id="Briefing">

				"The Earthican vessel Huygens Explorer seeks answers to questions.
				We help the vessel to seek answers throughout the system. But the
				vessel does not communicate. We fear the vessel struggles with
				danger. We fear the vessel ceases to exist.
				
				"The Earthican vessel Huygens Explorer needs help. Do you seek
				to journey to help them?"

			</Text>
			<String id="AcceptLabel">"[Y]es, I will help."</String>
			<Text id="AcceptReply">

				"We express relief. You will help the Huygens Explorer.

				"We give you coordinates to begin your search. The Earthican
				vessel is not there, but possible answers are there. We seek
				answers. Ringer and Earthican are united."

			</Text>
			<String id="DeclineLabel">"[N]o, I don't have time."</String>
			<Text id="DeclineReply">

				"We express surprise. We express sadness. The Earthican vessel
				Huygens Explorer needs help. Ringer and Earthican are opposed."

			</Text>
			<Text id="InProgress">

				The young ringer greets you:

				"We express surprise. Answers are not here. Answers exist out there."

			</Text>
			<Text id="textSuccessFoundROM">

				A group of ringers greet you. The young ringer is among them
				and he speaks through a translator:

				"We express sadness. The Earthican vessel Huygens Explorer
				ceases to exist. The collective diminishes. But answers exist.
				Information ROM exists that contains possible answers to Iocrym
				intentions. The sacrifice achieves purpose."

			</Text>
			<Text id="textSuccessSeekROM">

				A group of ringers greet you. The young ringer is among them
				and he speaks through a translator:

				"We express sadness. The Earthican vessel Huygens Explorer
				ceases to exist. The collective diminishes. But answers exist.
				Information ROM in wreckage contains possible answers to Iocrym
				intentions. Seek to retrieve the ROM and the answers."

			</Text>
			<Text id="textBusy">

				A young ringer greets you as you enter the lab:

				"Earthican, welcome! We seek answers to questions related to Iocrym.
				Return here once your other task is done and seek answers with us."

			</Text>
			<Text id="SuccessMsg">Huygens Explorer destroyed!</Text>

			<Text id="textLog">
				Huygens Explorer\n
				Captain's Log
			</Text>
			<Text id="textLog1">

				The signal that we were tracking led us to an interesting discovery:
				the wreck of an Iocrym sentinel with an intact AI core. It must have
				been destroyed in a battle because we found several Luminous drone
				wrecks nearby.

				We've taken the sentinel's AI core onboard in hopes that it will 
				help us to understand the Iocrym and what they are doing.

				We've deployed a log buoy marking this location and attached the
				coordinates of our next destination.

			</Text>
			<Text id="textLog2">

				In studying the sentinel's AI core we have learned a lot more about
				the Iocrym. They are an ancient race bred to be guardians and
				defenders. Their role is to protect other civilizations from
				(unspecified) threats originating at the periphery of the galactic
				disk. Is it possible that they consider us to be a threat? It seems
				hard to believe considering how advanced their technology is.

				Chief Scientist Masud is eager to learn more from the AI. We have
				decided to connect it to the Huygens' mainframe in order analyze the
				information more quickly. Of course we have followed the standard
				quarantine procedures to ensure the AI cannot compromise our systems.

			</Text>
			<Text id="textLog3">

				In the last few days we have learned much from the sentinel's AI.
				Masud has made progress interpreting some of the Iocrym symbols and
				language. Much of the information that we're finding is actually
				about us (human beings, that is). It seems they are as curious about
				us as we are about them. More than curious, actually. They are almost
				obsessed; they are frantic to learn quickly, which is unnerving for
				an ancient race used to dealing in eons.

				The only problem we have to report is a fault in our communications
				array. The Huygen's mainframe indicates that we will be unable to
				send or receive for the next seven hours, but the outage will not
				affect our investigations.

			</Text>
			<Text id="textLog4">

				The sentinel's AI has shut down for unknown reasons. We have tried
				several times to re-establish a connection but to no avail. Masud
				is puzzled and he has begun an analysis of all data traffic between
				our mainframe and the AI.

				More worrying to us is a newly discovered fault in our main drive.
				The Huygens' mainframe believes the drive is damaged, but that it
				can be repaired. The onboard nanofacs are creating the necessary
				parts under computer control.

				Computer checksums and diagnostics reveal no mainframe problems;
				other manual checks show that the mainframe is correct in its
				diagnosis and repairs of the main drive. Nevertheless, the crew is
				uneasy, particularly since communications is still inoperative.

			</Text>
			<Text id="textLog5">

				The sentinel's AI has control of the ship! It must have exploited a
				vulnerability in the mainframe kernel or perhaps gained physical
				access to the databanks. We don't even know when the AI gained
				control...it could have happened the second we connected. We are
				going to try to disable the main drive, but if everything else fails
				we will attempt to overload the reactor.

				We have attached tracking signatures to this buoy that will lead to
				our current location. Whoever finds this log, please come and help us!

			</Text>
			<Text id="textWarning">

				RECORDED from astrokor.masud.9277huygens_explorer.rinc

				MESSAGE BEGINS\n
				Save yourselves... the buoy message is not from us...
				crew is already dead... Save yourselves: Destroy the Huygens!

				MESSAGE ENDS

			</Text>
			<Text id="textDockHuygens">

				You dock with the Huygens Explorer, but the airlock reports zero
				pressure inside. Peering in through the airlock window you see
				floating bodies and debris.

				Suddenly you feel the Huygens's engines kick into action.
				Your stomach fills with dread...

			</Text>
		</Language>
	</MissionType>

<!-- EVENT HANDLERS -->

	<!-- Huygens Explorer Event Handler	-->

	<Type unid="&evHereticHuygensExplorer;">
		<Events>
			<OnBehaviorStart>
				(block Nil
					(shpCancelOrders gSource)
					(shpOrder gSource 'hold)
					)
			</OnBehaviorStart>

			<OnAttacked>
				(if (and gPlayerShip (= aOrderGiver gPlayerShip)
						(= (shpGetOrder gSource) 'hold))
					(block Nil
						(sovSetDisposition &svSentinelAI; &svPlayer; 'enemy)
						(sovSetDisposition &svPlayer; &svSentinelAI; 'enemy)

						(shpCancelOrders gSource)
						(shpOrder gSource 'attack gPlayerShip)
						)
					)
			</OnAttacked>

			<OnOrdersCompleted>
				(block Nil
					(shpOrder gSource 'waitForEnemy)
					(shpOrder gSource 'attackNearestEnemy)
					)
			</OnOrdersCompleted>
		</Events>
	</Type>

</TranscendenceModule>
